MAKSOOD MOHIUDDIN

MAKSOODMOHIUDDIN.COM • 404.583.2124 • MAKSOOD@GMAIL.COM

SUMMARY

A technology enthusiast with more than twelve years of professional software development experience and a proven record of leading small to mid-size software development teams to deliver high-performing enterprise software solutions using various technologies and platforms.

EMPLOYMENT

Capital One Investing

July 2015 to Present

Senior Software Engineer (Consultant/Iconma)

Seattle, WA

- Successfully build and launched <u>Refer-A-Friend</u> product for Marketing and Analytics guild as Technical Lead which is projected to bring in \$15 million new assets under management for current fiscal year.
- Delivered the product by implementing micro service architecture, one of the first in the company to do so, using Angular JS, ASP.NET MVC 5, C#, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, NUnit & Spec Flow test framework.
- Fully embraced dev ops responsibilities and hand build the CI/CD pipeline using GitHub, Jenkins, Nexus, Chef and infrastructure as code using AWS Cloud Stacks.

Microsoft

March 2015 to July 2015

<u>Software Engineer IV (Consultant/Robert Half Technology)</u>

Redmond, WA

- UI architect of <u>XBOX Ambassadors Platform</u> that enable users to engage with Xbox community and get rewarded for it.
- Building a mobile-first and test driven web application using Bootstrap, Angular JS, ASP.NET MVC 5, C#, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Karma & Protractor test suits, Xunit test framework, Web API, Moq, & Unity DI.
- Cloud software development experience using Microsoft Azure's infrastructure management tools such as cloud services, service bus topics, subscriptions, SQL server instances, and storage.

Twentieth Century Fox

June 2014 to March 2015

<u>Lead Software Developer (Consultant/Robert Half Technology)</u>

Seattle, WA

- Delivered a secure & large-scale <u>Digital Asset Management System</u> to Fox that consolidate 1 million plus digital assets in a single web portal; resulting in savings of maintenance cost on existing systems.
- Responsibilities include lead and mentor a team of four developers, designing systems architecture, workload management to align business needs and advice the business as a consultant.
- Hands-on software development experience using C#, ASP .Net MVC 5, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, Angular JS, Underscore.js, WCF, Restful services, SOA and SQL Server.

Time Warner

October 2010 to June 2014

Expert Software Developer

Atlanta, GA

- Create scalable software products with high data quality for the strategic planning division to help monetize Time Warner's TV contents, which generates over \$4 billion advertising revenue annually.
- Lead software development efforts to enhance and maintain existing business critical sales solutions software products with a team of four resources to drive advertising sales and provide revenue forecasting across all Time Warner networks (CNN, TNT, TBS, and Cartoon Network etc.).
- Active participation in Media Camp, an industry leading media startup incubator program and Next Gen, a strategic business unit that monitors disruptive technologies within media ecosystem.

1

Maksood Mohiuddin 404.583.2124

Senior Systems Development Specialist

Xerox

Atlanta, GA

April 2008 to October 2010

• Engaged in multiple full software development life cycles of the Airport Parking Revenue Control Software System in major world airports, with an average of \$15 million revenue per implementation.

- Led software development team of eight in an onshore-offshore model for the web based airport-parking facilities motioning tool.
- Technical Lead for Airport Valet Software Systems team across North America.
- Build highly available embedded systems for airport parking entry and exit terminal gates.
- Product architect for Video Annotation Module that uses third party video surveillance systems to create a video feed bookmark system to prevent frauds.

EDUCATION

Online Master of Science in Computer Science in Interactive Intelligence

Jan 2015 - Present

Georgia Institute of Technology - College of Computing, Atlanta, GA

Courses: <u>Artificial Intelligence</u>, <u>Artificial Intelligence for Robotics</u>, <u>Knowledge Based Artificial Intelligence</u>, Computer Networks, Software Development Process.

Professional Master of Business Administration (MBA)

May 2011

University of Georgia - Terry College of Business, Athens, GA

Courses: Strategic Management, Ethics, Public/Managerial Accounting, Finance, International Finance, Marketing, Business Law, Economics, Operations Management, Leadership, Investment, Project Management.

Bachelor of Science in Information Systems

May 2003

University of Texas, Arlington, TX

Major Courses: Intro/Inter/Advanced Computer Programing, OO Programing, Software Development, MIS, Networking, Systems Design, Database Systems, Algorithm & Data Structure, Theoretical Computer Science.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages:

- C# (Proficient)
- ASP.NET (Proficient)
- C, C++, VB6, Objective C (Mid-Level)

Development Architecture:

NET Framework, iOS, Android, TFS, Git

Database & Operating Systems:

SQL Server, Oracle, No-SQL

Cloud & CI/CD:

AWS, Azure

- Angular JS 1.x (Proficient)
- JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS (Mid-Level)
- Python, Java(Mid-Level)
- MVC, MVVM, WCF, WPF, Web API, EF
- Microsoft Windows, Apple Mac OS X, Linux
- GitHub, Jenkins, Maven, Chef, Nexus

PERSONAL INTEREST

- Artificial intelligence, machine learning and disruptive technologies that may change the way we live.
- Travelling, running, biking, football, baseball, basketball, soccer and cricket.